Contact

adk3cx@virginia.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/ andreashepherd2018 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing

ICU

Medication Administration

Languages

Spanish (Limited Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

BLS-CPR Certification

Registered Nurse

Certificate of Controlled Substance Registration

CCRN

ACLS- CPR Certification

Honors-Awards

Sonja Hoel-Perkins Scholar Dean's List Fall '11

Dean's List Spring '12 Dean's List Fall '12

VALOR Scholar

Andrea Shepherd, DNP, CRNP, FNP-C, CCRN

Family Nurse Practitioner at MedStar Washington Hospital Center Washington D.C. Metro Area

Summary

Family nurse practitioner specializing in lung cancer screening and lung health, but experienced critical care registered nurse with a demonstrated history and commitment of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in advanced cardiac life support (ACLS), intensive care, acute care, continuous renal replacement treatment (CRRT), teaching, research, translating evidence into practice, and in project management. Strong healthcare services professional with a Doctor of Nursing Practice (DNP) and a Certificate in Teaching in Nursing and Health Professions from the University of Maryland, as well as a Bachelors of Science (BSN) from the University of Virginia. Jonas Nurse Leaders Scholar from 2016-2018.

Experience

MedStar Washington Hospital Center 6 years

Nurse Practitioner August 2018 - Present (1 year 11 months) Washington D.C. Metro Area

- Integral in developing a new, thriving outpatient lung cancer screening clinic within a large hospital from a concept into reality.
- Manages and coordinates the care of patients for lung cancer screening, including its findings, as well as patients with incidental pulmonary nodules found on any imaging.
- Performs tobacco cessation treatment and counseling to both cancer patients and patients at risk for cancer.

- Collaborates with the multidisciplinary team of pulmonologists, thoracic surgeons, radiologists, medical oncologists, radiation oncologists, etc. to provide stellar "patient first" care.
- National leader on managing incidental findings from lung cancer screening low-dose CT as evidenced by presenting nationally and serving on a national multidisciplinary committee.
- Received two national designations for the lung cancer screening program.
- Serves as an expert consultant in creating and maintaining lung cancer screening programs.
- Performs telemedicine as deemed appropriate.
- Coordinates and participates in community outreach events.
- Performs administrative tasks as deemed appropriate.

Critical Care Registered Nurse

July 2014 - August 2018 (4 years 2 months)

Medical ICU and various other intensive care units

- Managed the care of patients with complex medical problems by stabilizing the critically ill patients, administering medications and other therapies, participating in bedside procedures, responding to code situations, and traveling with the critically ill patients to off-the-unit procedures
- Provided ethical, holistic, and compassionate care to the hospital's most critically ill medical patients
- Provided one-on-one consultation at the bedside and collaborate with the healthcare team to ensure the achievement of best clinical outcomes for patients and their families
- Advocated for patients and their families
- Served as resource/charge nurse
- Precepted new hire nurses

- Served on the education committee
- Floated throughout the other intensive care units

University of Maryland Baltimore Graduate Teaching Assistant August 2016 - December 2017 (1 year 5 months) Baltimore, Maryland

Helped teach, tutor, and organize the doctoral health assessment course of approximately 100 students.

Salem Veterans Affairs Medical Center Nursing Extern May 2013 - February 2014 (10 months) Salem, VA

- 400 hours of nursing clinical experience in Med/Surg, MICU, SICU, ER, Mental Health, Primary Care, Women's Health, Infection Control, and shadowing four different nurse practitioners in primary care, women's health, mental health, & acute care
- Conducted a research project on Virtual Bedrails
- Attended EKG, project management, and leadership courses

Dogwood Village of Orange County Senior Living Registered Medication Aide/ Certified Nursing Assistant July 2011 - July 2013 (2 years 1 month) Orange, VA

Administered medications and treatments, assisted residents with activities of daily living

Dogwood Village of Orange County Certified Nursing Assistant October 2008 - July 2011 (2 years 10 months) Orange, VA

Assisted residents with activities of daily living

Education

University of Maryland

Doctor of Nursing Practice, Family Nurse Practitioner & Certificate in Teaching in Nursing and Health Professions · (2014 - 2018)

University of Virginia

Bachelor of Science in Nursing, Bioethics Minor · (2010 - 2014)

MG School of Health Professions

Certificate, Medication Aide · (2011 - 2011)

Orange County High School

High School Diploma with Honors and Nurse Aide Certificate · (2006 - 2010)